<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mitch Rivet</title>
    <link>http://mitchrivet.github.io/tags/blogging/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mitch Rivet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://mitchrivet.github.io/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Blog?</title>
      <link>http://mitchrivet.github.io/why-blog</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 22:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mitchrivet.github.io/why-blog</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As I begin my journey with this blog, here are the practical reasons I see blogging:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-generate-better-ideas&#34;&gt;1. Generate better ideas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although internet criticism can be exceedingly negative, there is a lot of important feedback to be gained from opening your projects, plans, and thoughts to the online world. How can you assume that your ideas are worth anything without allowing them to be tested and critiqued? Writing also forces us to clarify our thinking, truly owning our ideas. Blogging can help you step out of your comfort zone into the arena of public discourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-help-others-by-sharing-what-you-learn&#34;&gt;2. Help others by sharing what you learn&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though there are tons of online resources for learning programming topics, there is always value in sharing tutorials for niche subjects and explaining ideas using your own analogies and mental processes. I have often found explanations shared to me by my peers to be the most memorable. It&amp;rsquo;s also commonly said that the best way to learn something yourself is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.futurity.org/learning-students-teaching-741342&#34;&gt;teach others&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-regular-reflection-will-improve-your-process&#34;&gt;3. Regular reflection will improve your process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your blog can become a data set of personal assessments, allowing you to see what aspects of your workflow are helping you or hindering you. In this sense, blogging combines the reflective process of journaling with a method to improve your ability to showcase your own work. By logging the successes and failures of your projects over time, you can gain a more macro sense of your accomplishments rather than a micro impression of one particular work day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-create-social-accountability&#34;&gt;4. Create social accountability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing your goals with others is a way to help push yourself to actually finish them. By posting about a project, you&amp;rsquo;re essentially making a promise to the internet that you will actually, eventually finish it. It&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to let an idea fall by the wayside when no one is holding your accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-if-your-work-is-not-online-it-doesn-t-exist&#34;&gt;5. &amp;ldquo;If your work is not online, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taken from the lovely book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00GU2RGGI/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Show Your Work!&amp;rdquo; by Austin Kleon&lt;/a&gt;. Today more than ever it is important to maintain an online presence for your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to include software development tutorials, notes from the topics I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying, as well as essays about music and audio production. Whenever I finish a book, I will also share the notes I took and my opinion of it, inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://sivers.org/book&#34;&gt;Derek Sivers&lt;/a&gt;. After blogging for a while, I will write a follow post to share what effects I have experienced from this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>